#### **ALEXIS BROWNSTEIN**

MULTI-LINGUAL TECH LEADER & PROJECT MANAGER

Creative-thinking, versatile technology leader with 15+ years of experience in business analysis and management of **enterprise-wide business technology projects**. Valued business partner **to all levels of an organization** with extensive experience in data analysis and mapping, plus all areas of the software development life cycle (SDLC).

## Certifications

2023 (anticipated) – Project Management Professional – PMP (PMI)

2023 - Certified Scrum Master (CSM) (Scrum Alliance)

2023 - Jira Work Management Fundamentals Badge (Atlassian)

2023 - Confluence Fundamentals Badge (Atlassian)

1993 - Certified in Production & Inventory Management - CPIM (APICS)

## **Education**

JavaScript Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp, Certificate

Rutgers University, 08/2022 - 02/2023

Completed a 24-week, virtual immersive web development program

Master's in Business Administration, M.B.A., Rutgers University

Bachelor's in French, B.A., Rutgers University

## **Experience**

Business Analyst Consultant @ Menarini Silicon Biosystems (08/2022 - 10/2022)

- Contractor for the largest privately-held biotech company in the world via Tatum by Randstad.
- Partnered with executive leadership team and CFO on financial planning and reporting, financial capabilities expansion, and technology innovation.
- Delivered business analysis and report development aspects using various systems and databases.
- Led and consulted in the planning, creation, and maintenance of complex dashboards/reports to analyze, manage, and report strategic financial insights.
- Pioneered efficient automated financial reports by leveraging VBA in Microsoft Excel and Access.
- Strengthened financial reporting capabilities by developing system proposals.
- Applied skills: Google workspace, proposal writing, Visio flowcharts

#### Technical Project Manager @ Universal Display Corporation (02/2007 – 04/2022)

- Effective senior leader for full development lifecycle of strategic, large-scale technology and business analysis projects.
  - Oversaw 15 project team members for on-time and on-budget delivery of the eQMS/EHS SaaS system deployment (ETQ Reliance).
  - Collaborated with project stakeholders, including vendor consultants, to review user stories, write requirements documentation, deliverables and progress tracking.
  - Significantly reduced release timelines and operational costs through design and integration of automated tools and reports.
  - Managed, planned and delivered user training sessions on software implementations and changes.

#### **Personal Info**

Phone Number (856) 912-1376

Email

alexis@drdatabase.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexisbrownstein/

Website

https://tinyurl.com/alexis-portfolio

## **Skills**

Cross-functional team leadership

Change management

Asset management

Technical & user documentation

Database design & management

Software development

Vendor management

Automated report creation

Quality assurance & management

Scrum & agile principles

**Training** 

Continuous learning

**Customer support** 

Effective verbal & written communication

Fluent in French & proficient in Spanish

Adaptability / flexibility / collaboration

Problem-solving

Data migrations

UAT / release management

Love of learning / emotional intelligence

# **Technical Project Manager @ Universal Display Corporation** (02/2007 – 04/2022) (CONTINUED)

- Applied project management skills and principles to improve efficiency and optimize processes.
  - Optimized enterprise systems and created user-friendly software applications, increasing employee productivity by more than 400%, saving millions of dollars in man-hours, as the company grew in market size.
  - Planned and prioritized project activities and tasks based on deadlines, resources, risks in R&D, Commercial, and Quality Assurance environments.
  - Led project meetings to evaluate progress, identify and mitigate risks, and amend project plans for overall project reporting.
  - Liaised with product owners, users and vendors to solve application and development issues while managing customer-facing issues.
- Elevated technological capabilities by building legacy SQL Server and Microsoft Access databases and Excel automation tools, and implementing enterprise systems.
  - Reduced project costs by 25% by taking on additional responsibilities, such as custom programming, that would have otherwise been completed by contractors.
  - Crafted comprehensive technical, user, and training documentation, including release notes.
  - Spearheaded releases for standard software updates, custom software changes and bug fixes.
  - Strengthened enterprise system security and configurations as System Administrator of ETQ Reliance.
  - Leveraged ETQ Reliance, SQL Server, Microsoft Access, and Microsoft Excel to design interfaces for data migrations.
  - Applied SQL Server to design and implement the company's first data warehouse for test data storage.
  - Reviewed and analyzed data and user group permissions (Active Directory/ SQL Server).
  - Capitalized on complex SQL queries, views, stored procedures, and SQL Agent to create critical and personalized business systems.

# **Technology**

ETQ Reliance (QMS, EHS)

ERP, MFG and CRM systems

Microsoft Access, SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB, NoSQL

Zoom, Teams, Slack, Miro

Microsoft Office, Visio

APIs

Git/Github

**VS Code** 

Bootstrap, Materialize

SQL, VB/VBA, ASP, VBScript, PHP, HTML, JavaScript, CSS

Salesforce

Jira, Confluence

### **Interests**

Enjoys sports, especially tennis, pickleball, volleyball, and kayaking

Loves to travel and recently visited Morocco, Jordan and Cuba

Interested in different languages and cultures from around the world

Trekkie